ifcc.org 2019-07-11

# Privacy Policy & Cookies - IFCC

**The International Federation of Clinical Chemistry and Laboratory Medicine (IFCC)  
respects your right to privacy**

The **International Federation of Clinical Chemistry and Laboratory Medicine (IFCC)** does not register any personal information about our visitors with the exception of what you choose to supply when subscribing to our newsletter or filling out contact forms. We do not pass on or sell personal information about our site visitors to third parties.

IFCC wants to make you comfortable with our privacy policy and the security measures that we take to protect your personal information. If you give IFCC personal information IFCC will treat it according to this policy. IFCC encourages you to read this privacy policy.

By using IFCC' Site, you consent to the collection and use of your information by IFCC as set forth in the policy below. IFCC reserves the unilateral right to update, modify, change and alter its privacy policy. All such updates, modifications, changes and alterations are binding on all users and browsers of the IFCC Site and will be posted here.

 **Types and Uses of Personal Information**

IFCC collects personally identifiable information, including name, title, company, address, e-mail address, phone numbers, etc. when a visitor to a IFCC Site registers to become a "registered user". IFCC does not require this information to obtain access to any part of the Site that is open to the public.

 **Traffic data**

In order to improve constantly IFCC for the benefit of our visitors, we collect information about the geographic location of your network, browser and platform, pages visited, duration of visit and referring site. We use cookies in connection with collection of these statistics.

The data we gather is used only in aggregated reports, for use by the IFCC Consortium and is shared only with our sponsors, exhibitors and business partners. It is not possible to identify you personally from this information.

 **Emails**

We endeavour to respond to any emails sent to IFCC. All correspondence is treated confidentially.

By subscribing to our newsletter, you consent to receive newsletters from us by email. It is possible to unsubscribe from this newsletter at any time.

 **Surveys**

From time to time, we may request information through surveys. Participation is voluntary and any information supplied by you will be treated confidentially. Survey data will be used exclusively to improve this website and the service we offer our visitors.

 **IFCC uses cookies**

IFCC is aware of its responsibility to society in general and to our individual customers and web site visitors in particular.

A cookie is a data file stored on your computer. At IFCC we use cookies to identify errors on the website and analyse your use of it.

We hope you will allow the cookies to be stored on your computer, as they help us improve your experience on the website.

 **If you don’t want to accept cookies from us:**

You may refuse to allow cookies on your computer by selecting the appropriate settings in your browser. Be aware that without cookies you may not be able to use all the website features. It is always possible for you to view, modify or delete cookies stored on your computer.

If you wish not to receive cookies from IFCC, in most browsers you can select advanced cookie settings under internet options and add this domain to the list of websites you want to block cookies from.

If you set your browser to block cookies, please be aware that there may be functions on IFCC that do not work.

 **What are cookies?**

A cookie is a data file that websites store on your computer in order to recognize your computer the next time you visit the website. Cookies are sent back and forth between your browser and a Web server and contain information such as:

  * user preferences
  * contents of cart
  * whether a user is logged in
  * how the website is used

A cookie file is passive and cannot spread computer viruses or other malicious programs. Often they help to analyse how the website is used in order to improve the user experience. In several cases, cookies may be necessary to provide a service.

Cookies usually are deleted automatically from the browser when it is closed (so-called session cookies). Cookies can also be set with an expiration time so that data exists for a shorter or longer period (persistent cookies). Persistent cookies are usually stored on the hard disk.

You can learn more about cookies and how to disable/enable them [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).
